JACQUELYNN ENNIS

574 West End Ave, New York City, NY 10024 • +1 (347) 277-2539 • jacquelynnennis@yahoo.com

SUMMARY

Motivated recent graduate with a master's degree in Computational Social Science, experienced in complex statistical and machine learning methods applied to research and problems in social science. I am excited to apply these skills to research in data analytics, using my background in teaching and experiences abroad to easily adapt to new situations and communicate findings in an accessible manner.

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computational Social Science

Aug 2021 - Dec 2023

Linköping University

• Thesis "Influencers in Confinement: Measuring Covid-19's Impact on Leadership in Pro-Eating Disorder Twitter Communities"

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology

Jun 2005 - May 2009

University of Mississippi

• Second major in Mandarin Chinese

WORK EXPERIENCE

Kindergarten Homeroom Teacher

Oct 2018 - Jul 2021

Beanstalk International Kindergarten - Kunming, China

- Employed various assessment strategies to evaluate student performance
- Designed lesson plans that fostered the cognitive, social and emotional development of early years learners
- · Collaborated with colleagues to design and implement early years international education curriculum

ESL/Subject Teacher Sep 2016 - Oct 2018

Kunming Foreign Language School - Kunming, China

- Designed and taught IGCSE Economics courses for high school students preparing to study abroad at international universities
- Instructed students in IELTS speaking and reading to attain English proficiency necessary for study abroad in English administered university programs
- Created and implemented lesson plans according to middle school English language curriculum

ESL Teacher Sep 2013 - Sep 2016

Web International English - Kunming, China

- Delivered English language instruction in listening, speaking and reading skills to beginner to advanced level students through a variety of teaching methods, including communicative approaches, interactive student led activities and multimedia resources
- Lead social clubs with 10+ students, creating engaging topics and facilitating discussion and debate in English

Library Assistant Mar 2011 - Sep 2013

Auckland City Libraries - Auckland, New Zealand

- Provided customer service to library patrons by assisting with inquiries, helping to locate materials, and offering guidance on library policies and procedures
- Managed check-in and check-out procedures, including the use of library systems, ensuring accuracy in cataloging, and processing interlibrary loans

SKILLS

- **Technical Skills:** Regression, Social Network Analysis, Agent-Based Modelling, Machine Learning, Research Design
- Programming Languges: R, Netlogo
- Languages: English, Mandarin